别吐出来
Don't let it out.
差一点
I can't.
我没事
I'm okay.
你确定？
Are you sure?
你打得很好
You fought well.
一旦你醒来
Once you woke up.
我没睡着
I wasn't sleeping.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我来吧
I'll do it.
阿拉肯 北厄拉科斯星球首府
拉 拉班大人
Lord Raban.
现在香料田已经安全了
Now that the spice field are secured,
我强烈建议将所有军队
I strongly recommend bringing all troops
撤出弗雷曼人的区域
out of Fremen territories.
我们在沙漠里损失了太多人
We're losing too many men to the desert
老鼠
Rats.
你说什么？
I beg your pardon?
我们损失的人……
We're losing them...
给了老鼠
To rats.
弗雷曼人
Fremen.
我无法确认 大人
I can't confirm, my Lord.
在开阔的沙地上通讯很混乱
Communications are hectic in the open sands.
你的任务
Your orders,
是控制整个星球
were too control the whole the planet.
我们有……
We have–
这只是一半
That's only half of it.
你可能还记得 南方不适合居住 大人
As you may recall, the south is uninhabtable, my Lord
我建议你休息一下 好吗？
May I suggest you get some rest?
老鼠！
Rats!
杀光他们！
Kill them all!
老鼠！
Rats!
他问我们为什么迟到了
He's asking why we're so late.
他认为你们是间谍
He thinks you're spies.
这里不欢迎你们
他说……
He said...
我听懂了
I got that.
谢谢
Thanks.
跟紧我
Stay close to me.
塔布尔穴地
Sietch Tabr
詹米! 詹米！
你杀了詹米！
间谍！
女巫！
住手! 住手！
他们不知道自己在说什么
李桑·阿尔-盖布! 李桑·阿尔-盖布！
救世主！
我需要你指引我们怎么处理那两个外国人
把他们交给沙漠
我看到了征兆
又来了
斯第尔格 你的信仰蒙蔽了你的双眼
李桑·阿尔-盖布还没出世呢！
他在一场公平的决斗中战胜了詹米
他会说我们的语言
他很快就会学会我们的生存之道
我愿意为他献出生命
沙漠将决定他的命运
那个女人呢？
看来贝尼·杰瑟里特的宣传已经深入人心
Looks like the Bene Gesserit's ' propaganda has taken root
有些人已经认为我是他们的救世主了
Some of them already think I'm their messiah.
其他人 则认为我是假先知
Others, false prophet.
我必须说服那些不信的人
I must sway the non-believers.
如果他们跟着我 我们就可以
If they follow me, we can
破坏香料生产
disrupt spice production.
只有这条路我才能接近皇帝
That's the only way I can get to the emperor.
你父亲不相信复仇
Your father didn't believe in revenge.
我相信
Hell, I do.
怎么了？
What is happening?
外国人吃不了辣？
怎么回事？
What is it?
食物里有香料
There's spice in the food.
他蓝眼睛一定很好看
别嘲笑他
他值得我们尊重 他是个好战士
女人 跟我来
Woman, come with me.
放回井里 我们的水回来了
我们祝福我们的兄弟 詹米
三千八百万公升
38 million decaliters.
我们即使渴死
None of us, even dying of thirst
也不会喝这的水
would ever drink this water.
这是神圣的
This is sacred.
创世纪之水
Genesis water.
我们有几千个这样的地方
We have thousands of places.
我们有足够的水源
where we have enough water.
李桑·阿尔-盖布将会
The Lisan al-Gaib will
改变厄拉科斯星球的面貌
Change the face of Arrakis
它将使树木重生 它将使……
It will bring back trees, it will bring back...
绿色天堂重现
a green paradise.
这么多灵魂
So many souls
永远不要把你的水给别人
Never give your water away,
即使死人也不行
not even for the dead.
你为什么带我看这些？
Why are you showing me this?
因为你是贝尼·杰瑟里特
Because you are Bene Gesserit
因为你了解预言
Because you understand the prophecies.
李桑·阿尔-盖布的母亲
The mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
会成为圣母
will be a Reverend mother.
我们的圣母快死了
Our Reverend Mother is dying.
你想让我代替她？
You want me to take her place?
是的
Yes,
我想
I do.
你相信保罗吗？
Do you believe in Paul?
有征兆
There are signs.
是的
Yes.
如果我拒绝呢？
What if I would refuse?
那他就不是李桑·阿尔-盖布
Then he is not Lisan al-Gaib,
你就没有任何意义了
And you have no purpose to serve.
那你还能做什么？
What else is left to do then?
把你的水放回井里？
But return your water to the well?
这是种荣誉 不是吗？
It's an honor, isn't it?
我觉得你应该感到荣幸
I think you should feel honored.
这是生死决择
It was a choice between this or death,
所以请原谅我的不敬
so forgive me if I'm not flattered.
一个人怎样才能当上圣母？
How does one become a Reverend Mother?
不同的文化是不同的
It's different from one culture to another.
在厄拉科斯星球 我不知道
Here on Arrakis, I have no idea.
你害怕了
You're afraid.
圣母肩负着
A Reverend Mother has the task
保存他们以前历代圣母的
of holding the memories
全部记忆的使命
of all the Reverend Mothers that came before them,
所以我会被赐予几个世纪的痛苦与悲伤
so I'll be given centuries of pain and sorrow.
危险吗？
Is it dangerous?
对男人来说是致命的
It's lethal for men.
绝对是
That's for sure.
你们在笑什么？
What are you guys laughing about?
别管了
Don't bother.
你不相信这一切？
You don't believe in all this?
不 我们不信
No, we don't.
这些都是南方的信仰
These are all Southern beliefs.
南方的信仰？
Southern beliefs?
南方部落相信弥赛亚
Southern tribes believe that a Messiah
会来拯救我们脱离邪恶
will come to deliver us from evil.
你不相信李桑·阿尔-盖布？
You don't believe in the Lisan al-Gaib?
我们相信弗雷曼人
We believe in Fremen
阿门
你想控制别人？
You want to control people?
你告诉他们救世主会来
You tell them a Messiah will come.
然后他们会等上几个世纪
Then they'll wait, for centuries.
现在 我们必须祈祷
Now, we must pray.
他怎么了？
What about him?
斯第尔格？
Stilgar?
他是南方人
He's from the South.
你没注意到他的口音
You didn't notice his accent.
我妈妈会怎么样？
What'll happen to my mother?
她会喝沙虫的尿
一点都不好笑
他就要失去她了
如果她蠢到喝毒药的话
住口！住口！
我们在祈祷
这是生命之水
它能解放心灵
如果你喝的话
你就会死去
你可以看见
喝！
这是什么？
我们做了什么？
她怀孕了
那不是奇迹！
你亲眼看到的！
李桑·阿尔-盖布的母亲
将在神圣的毒药试炼中幸存
她做到了
像书上写的那样！
那是她的族人写的！
亵渎神明
预言已经实现了
救世主必须是弗雷曼人！
厄拉科斯必须由自己的人民来解放！
她说得对 她说得对
She's right.
这不是奇迹
It's no miracle.
我妈妈受过这方面的训练
My mother was trained to do that.
把毒素转化成别的东西
Poison transmutation is something
高级贝尼·杰瑟里特可以做到
advanced Bene Gesserit can do.
我不是救世主
I'm not the Mahdi.
我不是来领导的
I'm not here to lead.
我是来学习你们的生存之道的
我在这里与你们并肩作战
I'm here to fight beside you.
这是我唯一的要求
That's all I'm asking.
我很谦虚地说他是救世主
更有理由相信他是！
像书上写的那样！
她怎么样？
How is she?
她很害怕 但她没事
She was frightened but she's okay.
她跟我说话
She talks to me.
她相信你
She believes in you.
她说
She says
魁萨茨·哈德拉克给我们指明道路
你就快成功了
You're so close now.
只有一步之遥
Only one step remains.
你会成为魁萨茨·哈德拉克
you will become the Kwisatz Haderach.
只有一步之遥
Only one step remains.
你必须像我一样
You must do what I did.
你必须喝下生命之水
You must drink the water of life.
你会解放心灵 你将看见
Your mind is gonna open and you will see.
你将看见！
美丽与恐怖！
如果你想和我们并肩战斗
If you want to fight with us,
首先你必须学会
first thing you must learn
与沙漠融为一体
to be one with the desert.
这里有帐篷和足够的食物
So here is a tent and enough food.
我要你走到那个小沙丘 然后返回
I want you to cross that small erg and come back.
晚上回来
Come by night.
你知道怎么用指南针
You know how to use a paracompass.
会的
Yes.
还有什么我需要知道的吗？
Anything else I should know?
除了沙虫和哈克南人
Beside the worms and the Harkonnens,
小心土蜘蛛
beware of the trap door spiders.
蜈蚣也很讨厌
Centipedes are very nasty.
不是那些大的
Not the big ones.
大的无害
They are harmless.
但小的你就要注意了
But the little ones you have to worry about.
千万 千万别听巨灵的话
Don't ever, ever listen to the Djinn.
巨灵
The Djinn.
巨灵 沙漠之魂
Djinn, desert spirits.
他们在夜晚轻言细语
They whisper at night.
他们会魅惑你
They can possess you.
真的 小心点
Really, be careful.
他们是恶魔
They are demons.
但这是真的
But it's true.
别听他们的
Don't listen to them.
他不知道如何穿越沙地
斯第尔格会害死他的
他想证明什么？
你觉得呢？
“先知必知道沙漠的道路”
我觉得这样最好
是不是这样？
你现在关心他了？
他和其他陌生人不一样
他很真诚
詹米
Jamis
你走起路来像只喝醉的蜥蜴
You sand walk like a drunk lizard.
是么 目前为止我做得还不赖
Yeah, I'm doing pretty good so far.
我们还没进入沙虫的地盘呢
We're not even in worm territory yet.
你得打破你的节奏
You have to break up your rhythm.
像这样
Like this.
这很有趣 因为在胶片书里
Now that's interesting because in the film books
我研究过 人类学家说
I've studied, the anthropologists say in order
你必须按照一定的规律，才能在沙地上行走
to properly sand walk, you actually have to.
算了
Nevermind.
请继续
Please keep going.
你知道 我是唯一一个相信
You know, I'm the only one who believes
你会撑到夏天的人
you're gonna make it until summer.
如果你想在沙漠里跟上我们
If you wanna follow us in the desert,
你就得知道捕风器的原理
you need to know how wind traps work.
所以听我说
So listen to me.
我总是觉得很简单
It's always neat to me.
它们很简单 但需要时刻留意
They're simple, but they require constant attention.
啥？
What?
别这样看着我
Stop looking at me like that.
你说得对
You're right.
如果我们想保护你的哥哥
If we want to protect your brother,
我们需要所有弗雷曼人都相信预言
we need all the Fremen to believe in the prophecy.
我们必须一个接一个地改变不信者的信仰
We must convert the non-believers one by one.
我们得从弱者开始
We need to start with the weaker ones.
意志簿弱的人
the vulnerable ones.
那些害怕我们的人
The ones that fear us.
契妮！
Chani!
装弹
Reload.
屏蔽场 只有直升机开火时才会关闭
The shield. They only open when they're firing.
我知道
I know that.
你以为我在做什么？
What do you think I'm trying to do?
我做引子
I'm triggering.
等我信号
On my signal.
准备
Be ready.
哦 该死
Oh shit.
你看到他做了什么
他早就料到了
他救了她的命
他看到了
他能预见
穆阿迪布喜欢他的味道
谁教你这样战斗的？
Who taught you to fight like that?
我以前的师傅
My old masters.
他们是很要好的朋友
And they were close friends.
他们被屠杀了 和我父亲一起
They were a massacred. Alongside my father.
你们与哈克南人作战几十年
You've been fighting The Harkonnens for decades.
我的家族已经与他们争斗了几个世纪
My family has been fighting them for centuries.
他们的习惯 他们的思维方式 我了如指掌
Their habits, their ways of thinking. I know everything about them,
你们对沙漠了如指掌
You know everything about the desert.
你们驾驭沙漠的力量
You harness the very power of it.
我们可以一起阻止他们
We can stop them together.
让他们死无丧身之沙
Bury them in the sand where they belong.
让这个星球再次属于你们
So that this planet can be yours once more.
你要我们做什么？
What will you have us do?
你会怎么做 斯第尔格？
What would you do, Stilgar?
我会挥戈北上
I would strike even further north.
那我挥戈北上
Then I will go further north.
你越往北走
The further north you go,
你越可能死
the more likely it is you die.
我会死
也许你也会死
但其他人会继续前进
直到弗雷曼人获得自由为止 否则他们是不会罢休的
他应该加入弗雷曼敢死队
他需要个名字 斯第尔格
好样的！好样的！
我在你身上看到了力量
I see strength in you.
像友索一样
意思是“梁柱的底座”
过来 过来
Come, come.
在我们中间 你应该被称为友索
You shall be known among us as Usul.
友索
Usul.
现在 你加入了弗雷曼敢死队 成为一名战士
And now a Fedaykin is a fighter.
你还必须选一个
and needs a war name.
战斗用的名字
You must choose.
你们怎么称呼这只沙漠小老鼠来着？
How do you call the small desert mouse again?
穆阿迪布 穆阿迪布
Muad'Dib.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
哦 不 穆阿迪布是很聪明的
Oh no, Muad'Dib is wise.
穆阿迪布深知沙漠的生存之道
Muad'dib is wise in the ways of the desert.
穆阿迪布 能自己制造水
Muad'Dib creates his own water.
能辩别指向北方的星座
The constellation that points to the North
所以我们叫它穆阿迪布
we call Muad'Dib.
指引方向的人
The one who points the way.
这名字很有力量
That is powerful name.
现在你是我们的兄弟了
Now you are our brother.
保罗·穆阿迪布·友索
Paul Muad'Dib Usul.
嘿! 斯第尔格！
Hey! Stilgar!
父亲 我找到了自己的路
Father, I found my way.
真美啊
It's breathtaking.
看 这就是香料
Look, right there's spice
每当夕阳落暮的时候 厄拉科斯星球格外动人
Arrakis is so beautiful when the sun is low.
在你的家乡
Where you're from...
水真的是从天而降的吗？
Does water really fall from the sky?
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
卡拉丹有时会下一个星期的雨
Sometimes it rains for a weeks, in Caladan
你看这儿的沙子 想象全是水
Where you see sand here, imagine water.
我们的城堡就矗立在海边的悬崖上
Our castle stands on cliffs, over the sea.
就算你一头扎进去 也够不到底
If you dive in, you can't reach the bottom.
你跳进去了？
You dive in?
是的
Yes.
这叫游泳
It's called swimming.
我可不相信 友索
I don't believe you, Usul.
友索
Usul.
你的小名叫什么？
What's your secret name?
-塞哈亚 -塞哈亚
Sihaya.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是沙漠之泉
It means desert spring.
沙漠之泉
Desert spring.
我喜欢它
I love it.
我讨厌它
I hate it.
来自某个愚蠢的预言
It's from some stupid prophecy.
我更喜欢契妮
I prefer Chani.
那我也更喜欢契妮
I prefer Chani too, then.
你觉得斯第尔格会教我吗？
Do you think Stilgar will teach me?
骑沙虫？
To ride?
是啊
Yeah.
不 只有弗雷曼人才会骑沙虫
No, only Fremen ride worms.
我已经是弗雷曼人了 不是吗？
I've become one, didn't I?
只是名字 不是血脉
By name, not by blood.
你的血脉来自公爵 名门望族
Your blood comes from dukes, great houses.
我们这里没有
We don't have that here.
在这里 我们人人平等 男人和女人都一样
Here, we're equal, men and women alike.
我们这么做都是为了所有人的利益
We do for the benefit of all.
但我很想被你平等以待
But I'd very much like to be equal to you.
保罗·穆阿迪布·友索
Paul Muad'Dib Usul.
也许你可以成为弗雷曼人
Maybe you could be Fremen.
也许我会给你指明道路
Maybe I'll show you the way.
干得好 漂亮 太棒了
拉班
Raban.
弗雷曼人 在你眼皮底下发动袭击
Fremen attacks on your watch.
你的任务是恢复香料生产
Your orders were to restore spice production
全速开工
To full capacity.
你知道失败意味着什么吗？
Do you know what it means if you fail?
皇帝会让我们失去对香料的控制
The Emperor will take spice out of our control.
撸起袖子 拉班
Tighten your grip, Raban.
叔叔
Uncle.
不然我就撸你脖子
Or feel mine on your neck.
友索
Usul.
没事的
It's okay.
嘿
Hey.
我在这儿 我在这儿
I'm here, I'm here.
你已经很久
It's been a while since
没做那些噩梦了
you've had one of those nightmares.
告诉我 这次梦到了什么？
Tell me, what was it about?
一切都模糊不清
Nothing's clear.
只是一些片段
It's only fragments.
我在南方
I'm in the south,
追赶某个人
and I'm following someone
然后引发了一场圣战
And it triggers a holy war.
成千上万的人饿死
Millions and millions of people starving to death
都是因为我
because of me.
你长时间接触香料
You've been exposed to spice for a long time.
它能产生奇怪的梦
It can create weird dreams.
今天是个大日子
It's a big day.
我们可以让斯第尔格取消行动
We can ask Stilgar to call it off.
不
No
我没事
I'm fine
友索
Usul.
我亲手做的
I done it myself.
给
Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
不要在乎别人怎么看
Don't try to impress anyone.
你很勇敢
You're brave.
我们都知道
We all know that.
要简单
Be simple.
要直接
Be direct.
别耍花招
Nothing fancy.
Nothing fancy
嘿 我是认真的
Hey, I'm serious.
别耍花招
Nothing fancy
否则你会让我的心血付之东流
or you will shame my teaching
我不会让你丢脸的
I won't shame you.
我明白
I understand.
夏胡鲁今天决定你要么成为弗雷曼人
Shai Hulu decides today if you become Fremen.
要么你死
Or if you die.
嘿 穆阿迪布！
Hey, Muad'Dib!
给我们开开眼！
找条大的！
别担心
斯第尔格教得很好
玩笑开够了
这是最后的测试
哇 没见过那么大
加油 穆阿迪布
Hi Muad'Dib!
穆阿迪布
Muad'Dib!
像书上写的那样
圣母！
穆阿迪布驯驭了夏胡鲁
他称它为沙虫爷爷
有史以来最大的
像书上写的那样！
夏胡鲁将向天外之音的男孩臣服
保佑造物主和他的创造
夏胡鲁会不会知道救世主来了？
那就这么说出去
我知道他们会的
I know they do.
我们在北方的任务即将完成
Our task in the north is nearly done.
他们相信保罗
They believe in Paul.
现在我们去南方
Now we go South.
那里有数百万正统教派者
There are millions of fundamentalists there.
他们会在保罗到来时保护他
They will protect him when he comes.
魁萨茨·哈德拉克……
The Kwisat Haderach...
将在南方诞生
will be born in the south.
你会永远爱我吗？
我对你的爱至死不渝
As long as I breathe.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
契妮？
Chani?
会出事的
There will be trouble.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
契妮 你什么意思？
Chani, what do you mean?
他们看你的眼神
The way they're looking at you.
他们现在崇拜你
They're worshiping you now.
敢死队员指望你带他们打胜仗
The Feydaykins are counting your victories,
他们说你能预见未来
They say you can see the future.
……一定是李桑·阿尔-盖布
...must be Lisan al-Gaib
我不是弥赛亚
I'm no Messiah.
我是塔布尔穴地的一名敢死队员
I'm a Feydaykin of Sietch Taybr.
可是 我们中间有一位很好的贝尼·杰瑟里特
Yet we have a Bene Gesserit among us,
为你的传奇煽风点火
fanning the flames of your legend,
说你就是救世主
saying you're the one.
圣母！
你的轿子准备好了！
她说你应该和我们一起走
She says you should be coming with us.
你知道我不能
You know I can't.
她在问为什么
She's asking why.
因为我必须继续在北方战斗
Because I must continue fighting in the north
保护你们在南方的安全
to protect you down there in the south.
她说你一说谎她就能看出来
She says she can tell when you lie.
告诉她那是因为我们的母亲
Tell her that's because our mother
一直在散布危险的谣言
keeps spreading dangerous tales.
她现在在说什么？
What is she saying now?
她说你被爱情蒙蔽了双眼
She says you're blinded by love,
她还提醒你
And she reminds you that
你必须把你的手
you must reserve your hand
留给最具战略意义的联盟
for the most strategic alliance.
她还想知道你为什么不相信
She's also wondering why you don't believe
自己是谁
in who you are.
我相信
I do believe.
我相信我对这些人很重要
I believe I matter to these people.
我相信我正在改变这场战争
I believe I'm making a difference in this war.
我们快到城门口了
We're nearly at the gates of the city.
她不是这个意思
That's not what she means.
我知道她的意思
I know what she means.
难道你不认为我也
Do you not think I also
感受到了预言的重量吗？
feel the weight of the prophecy?
这不是预言
It's not a prophecy.
这是你一直在讲的故事
It's a story that you keep telling,
但这不是他们的故事 是你的
but it's not their story, it's yours.
他们应该由自己人领导
They deserve to be led by one of their own.
你们的人对这个世界的所作所为
What your people did to
令人心碎
this world is heartbreaking.
我们给他们带来了希望
We gave them something to hope for.
那不是希望！
That's not hope!
圣母 我们得走了！他们来了
我等着你
I'll be waiting for you.
我们所有人
All of us.
那些风暴看起来很糟糕！
Those storms look bad!
他们是南方的守护神
这是一次艰难的旅程
但夏胡鲁很强大
阿拉肯香料仓库
损失多少？！我们上次收成的80%！
How much?! 80% of our last crop!
[听不清]
[inaudible]
你不该离开警戒线的！
You shouldn't have leaved the security perimeter!
警戒线? ！
Security perimeter?!
就剩这些了[听不清]！
The rest are already [inaudible]!
弗雷曼恶魔可能和他们在一起！
The Fremen demon might be with them!
希望如此！
Hope so!
我们正在搜寻他们 大人
We're tracking them, my lord.
今天 我要穆阿迪布死！
Today, Muad'Dib dies!
老鼠逃不了
快！
穆阿迪布！
Muad'Dib!
出来受死！
Show yourself!
为了穆阿迪布！
For Muad'Dib!
穆阿迪布
Muad'Dib
一位新的弗雷曼先知
Some new Fremen prophet.
这不是我们第一次和弗雷曼人起冲突
It's not the first time we've had frictions with the Fremen.
没有这么严重的
Not of this magnitude.
那么 我亲爱的女儿
So, my dear daughter,
你会如何对付这位先知？
how would you deal with this prophet?
如果这位穆阿迪布是一个宗教人物
If this Muad'Dib is a religious figure,
你不能直接动用武力
You can't use direct force.
镇压只会使宗教兴盛发达
Repression only makes a religion flourish.
最终只能让你自食其果
You'll only end up humiliating yourself.
你低估了我的萨多卡军团
You underestimate my Sardaukhars.
你低估了凡人信仰的力量
You underestimate the power of faith.
公主殿下再一次证明了
Her Highness proves once again
她是我最聪明的学生
that she was my most acute student.
那就派刺客去
Then send assassins.
不 先知死后会变得更强大
No, prophets get stronger when they die.
让冲突继续下去
Let the conflict on.
让厄拉科斯星球陷入战争
Arrakis turn into war.
然后你会带来和平 成为救世主
You'll then bring peace, as a Savior
而你会成为一个令人敬畏的皇后
You'd be a formidable Empress
穆阿迪布 先知
Muad'Dib. The prophet.
指引方向的人
The one who points the way.
这些是我们自己的宗教风格 不是吗？
These are our own religious patterns, aren't they?
这是我们干的
This is our doing.
穆阿迪布 意思是沙漠老鼠
Muad'Dib. Means kangaroo mouse,
弗雷曼人一个不寻常的战斗名字
An unusual war name for a Fremen.
万一保罗·厄崔迪还活着呢
What if Paul Atreides were still alive.
够了 这件事绝不许说出去
Enough, this must not come out.
那怕连你父亲都不能知道 明白吗？
Even to your father's ears, understand?
尊命 圣母
I do Reverend mother.
如果保罗还活着 他很可能知道真相
If Paul is alive, he likely knows the truth.
如果各大家族都知道
And should the great houses learn
你父亲是清算厄崔迪家族的幕后黑手
that your father was behind the liquidation
你父亲将面临战争
of the Atreides, your father will face war
失去王位
and lose the throne.
那希望何在？
Then what hope is there?
希望？
Hope?
我们是贝尼·杰瑟里特
We are Bene Gesserit.
我们不希望 我们计划
We don't hope, we plan.
保罗不是我们唯一的希望
Paul is not our only prospect.
男爵最小的侄子
The Baron's youngest nephew,
菲德-罗萨·哈克南 将继承厄拉科斯星球
Feyd-Rautha Harkonnen, will inherit Arrakis.
他可能就是答案
He may be the answer.
菲德-罗萨？
Feyd-Rautha?
他有精神病
He's psychotic.
这无关紧要
That's irrelevant.
问题是 我们能控制他吗？
The question is, can we control him?
我打算找出答案
And I intend to find out.
你想来点小鲜肉吗 亲爱的？
Would you like some fresh meats, my darling?
肺 肝脏
Lungs, a liver.
你想要什么？
What would you like?
我听说今天很隆重
I hear they're big today.
为了这个特别的日子 你的新刀
Your new blades for this very special day.
菲德-罗萨男爵
Na-Baron Feyd-Rautha.
有点不平衡 是刀尖
A nudge unbalanced. It's the tip.
应该磨快一点
Should be sharpened.
出来
我不会像个傻瓜一样死去
I won't die like a fool.
杀了我吧
Kill me now.
今天不给你下药 厄崔迪人
No drug for you today, Atreides.
在我们耀眼的黑色太阳下
请热烈欢迎举行这些特别庆典的
我们的伟大领袖 弗拉基米尔·哈克南男爵
他今天大驾光临 观看
鲜血和荣誉的壮观场面
以庆祝我们敬爱的
菲德-罗萨男爵的生日
姐妹们 欢迎来到杰第主星
Welcome to Geidi Prime, sisters.
祝你们旅途愉快
I hope your travels were agreeable.
远道而来只是为了观看我们的希望
A long way to come just to watch our prospect
以命相搏 芬伦夫人
Risk his life, Lady Fenring.
别害怕
No fear.
这场角斗只是做做样子
This fight's all for show.
但我们会好好看看他的
But we'll get a good look at him.
为了庆祝我们的菲德-罗萨男爵
我们为您奉上特别节目
最后三个厄崔迪家族的标本
那个奴隶没有被下药
That slave isn't drugged.
这家伙走得很直
That grub is walking straight.
我们可以取消角斗
We can cancel the fight.
不要破坏侄子的生日
Don't spoil nephew's birthday.
生日快乐 亲爱的侄子
Happy birthday, dear nephew.
他们为什么不停止角斗？
Why do they not stop the fight?
计划中的计划
Plans within plans.
让我看看你的真本事
Show me who you are.
有意思
There he is.
退后
Stay back.
你打得很好 厄崔迪人
You fought well, Atreides.
他确实令人印象深刻
He'impressive, indeed.
那个奴隶没有被下药
The slave wasn't drugged.
你想杀了我？
You tried to kill me?
今早你还是个纨绔子弟
This morning you were a playboy,
但今晚你是大英雄 令人畏惧和羡慕的英雄
but tonight you're a hero, feared and envied.
我给你的礼物
My gift to you.
我应该把你淹死在浴缸里
I ought to drown you in that tub.
别这么冲动
Don't be hasty.
我还有一个礼物要送给你
I have another gift for you,
一个更大的
A bigger one,
厄拉科斯
Arrakis
- 拉班怎么办？- 怪他自己没能保护好香料生产
What about Rabban? He just failed to protect Spice production.
拉班将被重新发配
Rabban will be reassigned.
征服厄拉科斯 费德
Tame Arrakis, Feyd.
源源不断地生产香料 我就封你为皇帝
Free the Spice and I'll make you emperor.
皇帝？
Emperor?
怎么做？
How?
皇帝助我摧毁了厄崔迪家族
The Emperor helped me destroy the Atreides
他把自己的军队借给我差谴
He lent his own army to the cause.
这是重罪
A serious crime.
如果事情败露的话
If it came to light,
各大家族会联合起来反对他
the Great Houses would rise against him.
到那时 谁会坐上王位呢？
And then, who will sit on the throne?
菲德-罗萨
Feyd-Rautha
哈克南人！
Harkonnen!
你在跟踪我
You're following me.
是吗？
Am I?
我可能迷路了
I may have gotten lost.
你能带我走出这个迷宫吗
Will you show me the way out of this maze,
我的男爵大人？
My Lord na-Baron?
我们见过 不是吗？
We've met, haven't we?
我想没有
I don't think so.
我是玛戈·芬伦夫人
I'm Lady Margot Fenring.
我是来向你祝贺生日的
I'm here to honor your coming of age.
你不能进入这个区域
You're not allowed in this section.
你是怎么通过守卫的？
How did you get past the guards?
守卫？
The Guards?
请问你在这里做什么？
May I ask what are you doing here?
你不是来参加自己的庆典的
You're not taking part in your own celebrations.
你是贝尼·杰瑟里特
You're Bene Gesserit
你为什么这么说？
And what makes you say that?
我想起来了……
I remember now...
我昨晚梦见你了
I dreamed about you last night.
希望是个美梦
A pleasant dream, I hope.
别嘲笑我 女人
Don't mock me, woman.
我不敢
I wouldn't dare.
我知道你的贝尼·杰瑟里特小把戏？
I know your Bene Gesserit tricks?
你对贝尼·杰瑟里特了解多少？
And what do you know about Bene Gesserit?
告诉我
Tell me.
出什么事了？
Is something wrong?
我不认识这个地方
I don't recognize this place.
这是客房区
This is the guest wing.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
回房间
To my room.
到我这儿来
Come to me.
跪下
Kneel.
把你的右手放进盒子里
Put your right hand in the box.
一个高智商的反社会人格
A sociopath of high intelligence,
被残忍的、但是强烈的荣誉感所驱使
driven, cruel, but strongly motivated by honor.
他渴望被伤害
He yearns to be hurt.
他喜欢痛苦
He loves pain.
他能得到救赎吗？
Can he be redeemed?
他可以被控制
He can be controlled.
他在性方面很脆弱
He's sexually vulnerable.
还有呢？
And?
血脉已经安全
The bloodline is secured.
一名女性 如你所愿
A female, as you requested.
你做得很好 玛戈
You did well, Margot.
恕我直言 你为什么不亲自测试他呢？
Respectfully, why didn't you test him yourself?
身为一位母亲
I'm a motherly figure.
考虑到发生在
And based on what happened
他和他母亲之间的事情
between him and his own mother,
我可能难有作为
I didn't expect to be effective.
他和他母亲之间发生了什么？
What happened between him and his mother?
他杀了她
He murdered her.
欲望和羞辱
Desire and humiliation.
这就是他的手段
Those are his levers.
如果菲德-罗萨在厄拉科斯星球获胜
If Feyd-Rautha prevails on Arrakis,
我们该知道如何控制他了
We shall know how to control him.
菲德-罗萨男爵万岁！
厄拉科斯星球的新总督
把那个弗雷曼恶魔带来见我
Bring me this Fremen demon.
我们进来了！
We're in!
发财了
Juicy.
发财 发财
Juicy, juicy.
狂欢时间
Cooking time.
滚出去！
Get out of here!
来啊 打啊！
Come on, fight!
我们被弗雷曼人包围了
We're in deep Fremen shit.
你奶奶的
Holy mother.
我认得你的脚步声
I recognize your footsteps,
老不死
old man.
你小子 你小子
You young pup.
在厄拉克斯战役之后
Well, after the Battle of Arrakeen,
我能够通过交换
I was able to negotiate a
为幸存者争取到回家的机会
trip back home for the survivors,
全靠了这些家伙啊
thanks to these guys.
你为什么留下来？
Why'd you stay?
我想血债血还
I wanted blood.
拉班的头
Raban's head.
自从穆阿迪布把拉班逼疯以后
Since Muad'Dib has been driving Raban crazy,
走私生意相当赚钱
the smuggling business has been quite profitable.
哥尼·哈勒克 走私贩
Gurney Halleck the smuggler.
保罗·穆阿迪布
Paul Muad'Dib.
我听过很多关于穆阿迪布的故事
I've heard many stories about Muad'Dib.
没一个是好的
None of them pretty.
你看他们多恐惧
You see the fear.
你知道我们的资源有限
You know our resources are limited.
恐惧是我们仅有的
Fear is all we have.
你有多少人？
How many men with you?
200人
200.
200人? ！
200?!
你有没有意识到
Do you realize what you'd able to
200个人能做什么？
achieve with 200 men?
不可思议的战士
Incredible fighters.
邓肯说他们有几百万人
Duncan said there were millions of them.
在南方腹地 是的
In the Deep South, yes.
你还在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
只要几千个这样的人
With thousands of these guys,
你就可以控制整个星球
you could take control of the entire planet.
这是你父亲的梦想 你在害怕什么？
It's your father's dream, what are you afraid of?
嘿
Hey.
崇拜 哥尼
Worship, Gurney.
他们曾经是朋友
They used to be friends.
现在他们是追随者了
Now they're followers.
穆阿迪布 先知
Muad'Dib, the prophet.
这有什么不好的？
Why is that a bad thing?
好好利用
Use it.
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
你有能力为你父亲报仇雪恨
You have the power to avenge your father
而你却害怕使用它？
and you're afraid to use it?
香料开启了我的心智 哥尼
Spice opened my mind, Gurney.
我能预见未来
I could foresee things.
如果我去南方 我所有的幻象都会导致恐惧
If I go south, all my visions lead to horror.
数十亿的尸体散落在银河系各星球
Billions of corpses scattered across the galaxy.
所有人都因我而死
All dying because of me.
因为你失去了控制
Because you lose control.
因为是我一手控制
Because I gain it.
好多水啊
That's a lot of water.
契妮
Chani.
啥？
What?
看看他 他没救了
Look at him. He's hopeless.
他是我的家人
He's family.
真的？
Really?
你觉得这个外人怎么样？
我觉得他是个麻烦
不 我相信友索
不需要成为先知也能看见未来
Don't need to be a prophet to see what's ahead.
你的路通向战争
Your path leads to war.
你知道的
You know that.
现在战争即将来临
So war is coming.
你会怎么做
What will you do when you
当你感觉到战争已经迫在眉睫？
feel its breath upon your neck?
如果你不想在南方组织军队
If you don't want to raise an army in
你还有一个选择
the South, you still have an option.
火力 但你没有
Fire power, which you don't have.
而我来了
And here I am.
我知道你父亲把家族原子弹藏在哪里
I know where your father hid the family atomics.
每个家族都有一个原子武器库
Every House possesses an atomic arsenal.
我以为我们的已经丢失了
And I thought ours had been lost.
这是件大事 契妮 可以改变一切
It's huge, Chani. Could change everything.
我可以把原子弹对准主要的香料田
I could aim the bombs at the main spice fields.
“能摧毁它的人
He who can destroy a thing
才是真正控制他的人”
has the real control of it."
所以你能控制它 而不是我们？
So you can control it and not us?
你答应过我你不想要权力
You promised me you didn't want power.
不管我做什么 你还是不相信我
No matter what I do, you still don't trust me.
因为你是外国人 就像你的朋友一样
Because you're a foreigner. Like your friend.
我不是外国人
I'm not a foreigner.
对我来说不是 但对于沙漠来说
Not to me, but to the Desert you are.
我忠于你 忠于弗雷曼人
My allegiance is to you, to the Fremen.
我这么做是为了我们所有人
I'm doing this for all of us.
你相信我吗？
Do you believe me?
我去跟斯第尔格谈谈
I'll talk to Stilgar.
看那
There.
就在大家眼皮底下
It's right under everybody's noses.
真笨
Not clever.
就是这个意思 没人会注意那里
That's the idea. Nobody would ever look
因为太明显
in there because it's obvious.
真笨
Not clever.
你找到了吗？
Did you find it?
我就没找
I didn't look for it.
到底有多少弹头？
How many heads exactly?
足够炸飞整个星球
Enough to blow up the whole planet.
打个比方
It's a figure of speech.
你们知道的
You know what I mean.
只有你的遗传基因才能打开
Only with your genetic heritage.
你曾曾祖父的遗产
Your great, great grandfather's legacy.
92颗阿崔迪斯家族的原子弹头
The 92 original Atreides family's atomic warheads.
这 这就是力量
That. That is power.
帝国日记
Imperial diary.
10191年
Year 10,191.
评论八
Eighth comment.
来自厄拉科斯星球南部的报告很少
Reports from the south of Arrakis arrive rarely.
那是一片荒芜、焦黑的土地
These are barren, burnt lands, hidden by
被横跨千里赤道的沙暴所覆盖
sandstorms which stretch a thousand miles across the equator.
没有信仰 什么也活不下来
Nothing can live there without faith.
这就是为什么我们贝尼·杰瑟里特的传教士
Which is why our Bene Gesserit missionaries have
在那里工作成效特别显著
been so productive there.
通过他们 我们收到了
Through them we are receiving reports of
关于一个神秘人物的报告
a mysterious figure taking grip on the
这个神秘人物牢牢控制着
imaginations of the southern
南方正统教派部落的信仰
fundamentalist tribes.
一位来自北方的新教母
A new Reverend Mother from the North.
传播着天外之声
Spreading word of the imminent arrival of
李桑·阿尔-盖布
the Lisan Al-Gaib.
即将到来的福音
The voice from the outer world.
随着南方宗教狂热不断高涨
With religious fervor rising in the south
和穆阿迪布扼杀北方的香料生产
and Muad'Dibb strangling spice production in
所有这一切
the north, everything
表明战争威胁正在升级
points to the escalation of war.
一次只能有一条……
否则他们会自相残杀
今年几岁了？
非常年轻
我女儿问 这是怎么做到的？
安静
Quiet.
生命之水
仔细听着
Listen carefully.
很快就会有一个人来拜访你的寺庙
Soon a man is going to visit your temple
他可能想让你主持仪式
and he may want you to perform the rites.
圣母 这是被禁止的
Reverend Mother, it is forbidden.
你质疑预言？
没有人能活下来
让他试试
Let him try.
什么鬼？
What the hell?
契妮！
Chani!
契妮
Chani.
老式火炮
Old-fashioned artillery.
天才
Genius.
我们简直是在他们头上下石头
We're literally melting rock on their heads.
我想去地面
I want to go on the ground.
准备我的军队
Prepare my troops.
大人
My Lord,
我建议你待在……
I would recommend you stay inside the...
把他的尸体带到我的房间
Bring his body to my quarters.
我可怜的孩子们饿了
My poor darlings are hungry.
飞船上没有食物给他们吃
There was no food for them on the flight.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
大清早的
It's early morning.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
亲我的脚 兄弟
Kiss my feet, Brother.
你让我们家族丢尽脸面
You humiliated our family.
你羞辱了我
You humiliated me.
要么求我
Please.
要么死
Or die.
我们扯平了
We're even now.
再羞辱我们家族一次
Embarass the family one more time.
就没那么客气了
It will be the be the last.
他们都死了！
我在大火中失去了他们
他们甚至没有在地面交火
They didn't even engaged on the ground
就像光荣的战士一样
like honourable fighters.
整个北方都遭到袭击
有人呼吁在南方召开战争会议
每个领袖都必须参加
穆阿迪布 他们在等你
友索 在南方
Ushur, in the south,
只有领导人才有发言权
Only leaders are allowed to speak.
你必须代替我出席
You must take my place.
我做不到
I can't do that
现在是取代我的最好时机
It is a good time to cross blades with me.
我身负重伤
I am weak.
很容易把我杀死
I am an easy kill.
我宁愿砍掉自己的手
I'd rather cut off my own hand.
我们需要你
We need you.
我们需要李桑·阿尔-盖布
We need the Lisan al-Gaib
来领导我们的人民
to lead our people.
你知道我对这个传说的看法
You know what I think of that story
我不管你信不信
I don't care what you believe.
我相信
I believe.
我没想到会这样
I didn't see it coming.
哈克南家族的事还没完呢
The Harkonnens aren't done here.
他们只是回去重新装弹
They just went back to reload.
我们正在设置沙槌
We're setting Thumpers.
我们要把所有人转移到南边去
We're moving everyone to the South.
我留下来掩护你们撤退
I'll stay behind and cover your retreat.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
契妮 我不能和你一起走
Chani, I can't go with you.
你知道的
You know why.
我也留下
I'll stay too.
除了我 谁都不许留下
Nobody stays but me.
保罗
Paul...
这是命令 哥尼·哈勒克！
That's an order, Gurney Halleck!
去南方！
Go south!
保护我的母亲
Protect my mother.
尊命
My lord.
没有你 这些人是不会离开的
我不能去南方
他害怕正统教派者
He's afraid of the fundamentalists.
他应该害怕
He should be.
告诉我 詹米
Talk to me, Jamis.
魁萨茨·哈德拉克
Kwisatz Haderach.
你只能看见碎片
You see only fragments.
你只能看见未来
You can only see the future.
你没有看见过去
You haven't seen the past.
你需要喝下生命之水
You need to drink the Water of Life.
你就会看见一切
And you will see everything.
在狩猎之前 好猎手总是
The good hunter always climbs the highest dune
爬上最高的沙丘
before his hunt.
他需要看见
He needs to see.
看得越远越好
As far as he can see.
你也需要看见
You need to see.
你必须喝下生命之水
You must drink the Water of Life.
你的心智将会打开
Your mind is going to open.
你会看见的
And you will see.
对我们来说 这个世界有很多选择
The world has many choices for us.
如果去南方 我可能会失去你
If I go south, I might lose you.
我将永远爱你
You will never lose me.
保罗·厄崔迪
Paul Atreides
只要你还是原来的你
Not as long as you stay who you are.
我会和你一起穿越风暴
I will cross the storms with you.
去南方
Go South.
把我们的人带到安全的地方
Bring our people to safety.
然后我要做必须做的事
And then I will do what must be done.
男爵
除了这个断后的间谍
Spy. Left behind.
没有其他人的踪迹
No trace of the others.
他们往南走了 躲进沙暴中
They have gone south to hide in the storms.
把这个消息报告给男爵
Send this message to the Baron.
北方已经解放并且安全了
The North is liberated and secured.
随意收获香料
Harvest spice at will.
是的 男爵
Yes, na-Baron.
你只用这样一把刀就杀了我九名手下
You killed nine of my men with one single blade.
她不肯说
She won't talk.
告诉她没关系
Tell her that's fine.
该知道的我都知道了
I already know everything I need to know.
剩下的只有快乐
Only pleasure remains.
生人勿进
生存还是毁灭
我应该受到欢迎
如果你喝下 你就会死
如果你喝了 你就会看见
既然你能看见我们的过去
Now that you can see our past,
你就能看见你的未来
you can see your future.
你的未来……
Your future...
哥哥
My brother.
我最亲爱的哥哥
My dearest brother.
你还没有准备好去面对即将发生之事
You are not prepared for what is to come.
现在知道了我们家族的真相
Now learn the truth about our family
你会撕心裂肺……
and it will hurt you...
痛不欲生
...to the core.
保罗
Paul.
别担心
Don't worry.
我和你在一起
I'm with you.
我爱你
I love you.
谁知道这件事？
只有你 圣母
很好
其他人呢？
他们刚从北方过来
找到他们！
Find them!
保罗
Paul.
我在这儿 我在这儿
I'm here.
发生什么事了？发生什么事了？
What happened?
他死了
He's dead.
他的生命体征很低 无法检测
His vital signs are so low they can't be detected.
但他还活着
But he's alive.
你对他做了什么？
What did you do to him?
不 不会的
No, not that.
他为什么要这么做？
Why would he do that?
因为他是救世主
李桑·阿尔-盖布会找到他的道路的
去没有人去过的地方
你疯了！
契妮 他的身体在和毒素作斗争
Chani, his body is fighting the poison
他需要你的帮助
and he needs your help.
你来
You do it.
是你害了他
You did this to him.
你对自己的儿子做了这些
You did this to your own son.
你来
You do it.
你自己治好他
Fix him yourself.
契妮 你也许不相信预言
Chani, you might not believe in the
但你是预言的一部分
prophecy but you're a part of it.
你就是毒药
You're the poison.
你和你的谎言
You and your lies.
-你为什么要这么对我？ -做吧
Why would you do this to me? Do it.
他会死而复生
用沙漠之泉的泪水
给我一滴生命之水
像书上写的那样
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
是的
Yes.
你确定？
Are you sure?
多亏了你
Thanks to you.
契妮的事我很难过
I'm sorry about Chani.
她会理解的
She'll come to understand.
我看见了
I've seen it.
你能看见了
You can see.
现在幻象变得清晰
The visions are clear now.
我一下子看到了所有可能的未来
I see possible futures all at once.
我们的敌人无处不在
Our enemies are all around us.
这不是他们唯一的未来
That's not the only future they prevail.
我确实看到一条路
I do see a way.
有一条狭窄的通路
There is a narrow way through.
我看到了我们母亲的血脉
I saw our bloodline mother.
穿越时空
Written across time.
你是
You're the daughter of
弗拉基米尔・哈克南男爵的女儿
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
我父亲知道吗？
Did my father know?
我自己也不知道 直到
I didn't know myself until
我服下沙虫的毒药
I took the worm's poison.
我们是哈克南人
We're Harkonnens.
这就是我们存在的方式
So this is how we'll survive.
通过成为哈克南人
By being Harkonnens.
我们得谈谈
We must talk.
斯第尔格
Stilgar.
你可以阻止这一切！
You can stop this!
你听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
你有能力阻止这一切！
You have the power to stop this!
你不能在圈子里说话 北方女人
You're not to want to speak inside the circle. Northern woman.
如果你想说话 你知道该怎么做
If you want to speak, you know what to do.
斯第尔格 求你了
Stilgar, please.
厄拉科斯正在沉沦
Arrakis is sinking.
他们通过预言来奴役我们
This prophecy is how they enslave us.
这是他们的统治方式
How they dominate.
你会惹上麻烦的
You'll get yourself in trouble.
这不关你的事
This is none your business.
拉班·哈克南亲手杀了我的家人
Raban Harkonnen himself killed my family.
他给了我这道伤疤 让我记住他
He gave me this scar to remember him by.
这全是我的私人恩怨
This is all of my business.
穆阿迪布 只有部落首领才能说话
Muad'dib. Only tribe leaders can speak
如果你想发表你的声音
If you wish to share your voice,
你必须通过打败他来取代他的位置
You must take his place by defeating him
然后把他的水放回井里
and returning his water to the well.
你觉得我会愚蠢到褫夺一位
You think I'm stupid enough to deprive
我们当中最优秀的人
myself of the best of us.
你会在战斗前砸碎刀子吗？
杀了我吧 友索
Take my life, Usul.
这是唯一的途径
It is the only way.
我在指路！
I'm pointing the way!
慢一点
Slow down.
这个房间里没有……
……谁能对抗我
你的母亲警告过你我会来
害怕这一刻
但你觉得自己还有机会
But you think you could have a chance.
可你害怕了
如果我是你的救世主呢？
这可能是你一生都在祈祷的时刻
现在你在祈祷……
……向你的祖母……
……她九个月前去世了
她失去了一只眼睛
当她穿越沙暴时 一块石头砸中了她的脸
事情发生时 她才十二岁
当时 这个世界有一个弗雷曼人 他的名字叫
沙丘
Dune.
李桑·阿尔-盖布！
Lisan al-Gaib!
救世主
Mahdi.
在你的噩梦里
你给死去的人浇水
这让你的心充满了喜悦
救世主 你对我们的预测是什么？
绿色天堂
李桑·阿尔-盖布……
……给我们指明道路！
这是我父亲的公爵印章
This is my father's ducal signet.
我是保罗·穆阿迪布·厄崔迪 厄拉科斯公爵
I am Paul Muad'Dib Atreides, Duke of Arrakis.
上帝之手为我作证
我是天外之声
我会带领你们
上天堂！
保罗·厄崔迪还活着
Paul Atreides is still alive.
他向我父亲发起挑战
He challenges my father.
你从没踏足厄拉科斯星球
You've never been on Arrakis.
那里令人难以忘怀 你会看到的
It's quite impressive, you'll see.
这全是你的主意吗？
Was this all upon your advice?
什么？
What?
你建议我父亲消灭
Did you counsel my father
厄崔迪斯家族？
to exterminate the Atreides?
当然是我
Of course I did.
不然为什么会发生这种事？
Why else would it have happened?
你试图牺牲整个血脉
You tried to sacrifice an entire bloodline.
我这么做是对的
And I was right to do it.
魁萨茨·哈德拉克是一种力量
The Kwisatz Haderach is a form of power
我们的世界还从未见识过的
that our world has not yet seen.
终极力量
The ultimate power.
九十代以来
For ninety generations we have
监督着厄崔迪家族
supervised House Atreides.
他们很有前途 但他们
They were promising, but they were
变得非常危险
becoming dangerously defiant.
他们的血脉必须被终结
Their bloodline had to be terminated.
这就是为什么我们让许多血脉运作
That is why we have put many bloodlines at work.
几个有前途的
Several prospects.
但适得其反
But it's backfired.
保罗还活着
Paul is alive.
如果他打败了
And if he defeats.
维德拉瑟 我父亲……
Vaidrathir, my father is...
你父亲会失去王位
Your father will lose the throne, no
不管谁获胜
matter who prevails.
但是有一种方法
But there is one way your
可以让你的家族继续掌权
family can remain in power.
通过你
And through you, the
延续我们的统治
continuation of our stewardship.
只有一条路 你准备好了吗
One way. Are you prepared.
你一直在帮我安排
You've been preparing me my
我的一生 圣母
whole life, Reverend Mother.
你要和其他人一起去北方吗？
You're heading North with the others?
我是敢死队员
I'm feydaykin.
我跟随我的队长 如果
I follow my leaders. If
战斗往北 我往北
fighting goes north, I go north.
保罗别无选择 契妮
Paul didn't have a choice, Chani.
我不会为他而战
I won't be fighting for him.
我为我的人民而战
I'm fighting for my people.
我是来祝你好运的
I came to wish you best of luck.
我也祝你好运
I'd wish you the same.
但看起来你已经赢得了战斗
But it seems you've won your battle.
他们上钩了
They took the bait.
皇帝陛下真是兢兢业业
The Emperor is very obliging.
他很准时
He's right on time.
正如你所预见的 穆阿迪布
沙暴祖母要来了
他来这里做什么？
What is he doing here?
我控制了香料生产
I brought spice production under control.
我们该怎么办？
What do we do?
给各大家族发信息
Send messages to the great Houses.
告诉他们厄拉科斯正遭受
Tell them that Arrakis is
萨多卡的攻击
underer Sardaukar attack.
告诉他们 他们的未来岌岌可危
Tell them their future hangs in the balance.
他带来了整支军队
当沙暴袭击这里山脊时
When the storm hits this ridge,
哥尼会为你开辟道路 斯第尔格
Gurney will open the way for you Stilgar.
这样你就可以从西面进入盆地
So you can enter the basin from the west
吸引他们防御系统的注意力
and distract their defense systems.
契妮 我要你和你的敢死队员
Chani, I want you and your Feydaykins
从东面发起进攻
to then attack from the east,
杀入盆地
Inside the basin.
我率领正统教派军队从北面进攻
I'll strike from the north and head on
长趋直入
with the fundamentalist troops.
而我将拿下厄拉克斯 如探囊取物
And I'll serve Arrakeen for dessert.
记住 我要活捉皇帝
Remember, I need the emperor alive.
天佑勇士！
男爵 你可知道这个
Baron, do you have any idea who this
穆阿迪布是何许人？
Muad'Dib could be?
一些狂热分子 陛下
Some fanatic, your majesty.
我们就知道这么多
That's all we know.
更多 更多 告诉我更多
More. More, give me more.
-他是个疯子！ -疯子？
He's a madman! Mad?
所有弗雷曼人都是疯子
All Fremen are mad.
你们就知道这些 真的吗？
That's all you know, really?
穆阿迪布死了
Muad'Dib is dead.
或者他躲进南方的沙暴里
Or he went hiding in the southern storms.
反正是同一个意思
It means the same thing.
陛下 他们说的是真的 沙暴正在
Your majesty, the sandstorm that's They speak the truth.
逼近 威胁到我们屏蔽场的完整性
approaching threatens the integrity of our shields.
我们建议返回轨道
We recommend going back into orbit.
山脉会保护我们免受大部分沙暴的侵袭
The mountains will protect us from most of it,
陛下
your Majesty.
男爵 你有没有调查过厄拉科斯星球……
Baron, have you ever investigated the south...
的南部地区？
regions of Arrakis?
整个地区都不适合居住
All the entire region is uninhabitable.
这是众所周知的 陛下
It's well known, your Majesty.
你那无人居住的南方
Your uninhabited South,
有人类活动的迹象
exhibits evidence of human activity.
我并不知道
I wasn't aware of this.
我发誓 我什么都不知道
I swear to you, I wasn't aware of anything.
穆阿迪布还活着
Muad'Dib is alive.
必须找到他
I must find him.
天佑勇士！
外公
Grandfather.
你会像野兽一样死去
You die like an animal.
穆阿迪布
Muad'Dib.
把囚犯带到驻地
杀光萨多卡
把男爵的尸体交给沙漠
看看是谁死而复生了
为了公爵 为了朋友
战舰
War ships.
各大家族
The Great Houses.
哥尼 是时候了
Gurney, it's time.
把犯人带来
Bring the prisoners.
尊命
My lord.
这事还没完
This isn't over yet.
我想让你知道
I want you to know...
我对你的爱至死不渝
I will love you as long as I breathe.
轨道上集结了一支舰队
There's an amassed armada, in orbit.
你正面临全面入侵 弗雷曼人
You're facing a full invasion, Fremen.
你怎么能这么肯定
How can you be so sure the
各大家族到这里是为了我？
Great Houses are here for me?
他们可能很想听听我的说法
They may be curious to hear my side of
你不觉得吗？
the story, don't you think?
我是保罗·厄崔迪
I am Paul Atreides, son of
厄拉科斯公爵雷托·厄崔迪之子
Leto Atreides, Duke of Arrakis.
哥尼
Gurney.
大人？
My Lord?
向所有战舰发出警告
Send a warning to all ships.
如果各大家族进攻 我们就用原子弹
If the great houses attack, our atomics
摧毁所有香料田
will obliterate all spice fields.
你疯了吗？
You're out of your mind?
他在虚张声势
He's bluffing
仔细考虑你即将做出的事 保罗·厄崔迪
Consider what you're about to do, Paul Atreides.
闭嘴！
Silence!
讨厌
Abomination.
信息已发出 大人
Message sent, my Lord
当我站在帝国之上时 你将臣服于我的脚下
As I stand on the Imperium, you will bow at my feet
你的脚？
Your feet?
你能保住脑袋就算走运了
You'll be lucky to keep your head.
我会牵着你女儿的手
I'll take the hand of your daughter.
她会安然无恙 我们将
She will remain safe, and we will rule
共同统治帝国
together over the Empire.
而你……
But you...
你必须为我父亲的死负责
You'll have to answer for my father.
你知道我为什么要杀他吗？
Do you know why I killed him?
因为他是一个
Because he was a man who
相信内心律令的人
believed in the rules of the heart.
但人心是不能用来统治的
But the heart is not meant to rule.
换句话说 你父亲是个软弱的人
In other words, your father was a weak man.
要么迎战 要么选择你的勇士
Stand or choose your champion.
我在这里 厄崔迪人
I'm here, Atreides.
我需要一把刀
I need a blade.
请用我的
Accept mine.
别让这动物弄脏你的手
Do not stain your hands on this animal,
他们需要你和他们在一起
They need you with them.
这是我的责任 哥尼
It's my burden, Gurney.
他为什么要冒这么大的风险？
Why is he taking such risks?
穆阿迪布 指明道路
Muad'Dib leads the way.
很高兴终于见到你
I'm happy to finally meet you,
表弟
cousin.
表弟？
Cousin?
是吗？
Is that right?
好吧
Well.
你不会是
You wouldn't be the
我杀的第一个亲戚
first relative I've killed.
愿你刀毁人亡
May thy knife chip and shatter.
她是你的宠物吗？
She's your pet?
对宠物有什么特殊照顾吗？
Any special attention for the pet?
你打得很好 厄崔迪人
You've fought well, Atreides.
李桑·阿尔-盖布！
Lisan al-Gaib!
你应该相信的
You should have believed.
你选择了错误的一方
You chose the wrong side.
哪一方？
Side?
你应该最清楚
You of all people should know.
没有哪一方 圣母
There are no sides, Reverend Mother.
生命之债已经还清了
The life debt has been paid.
现在放了我父亲 我
Spare my father now and I
将成为你称心如意的新娘
will be your willing bride.
王位就是你的了
The throne will be yours.
大人 各大家族已经回应
My lord, the great houses have answered.
他们拒绝承认你的王位
They refuse to honor your ascendency.
我们等待你的命令 李桑·阿尔-盖布
We await your orders, Lisan al-Gaib
带他们上天堂
Lead them to paradise.
怎么了 妈妈？
What is happening, mother?
你哥哥袭击了各大家族
Your brother attacks the Great Houses.
圣战开始了
The Holy War begins.
导演 丹尼斯·维伦纽瓦
编剧 丹尼斯·维伦纽瓦 乔·斯派茨
根据弗兰克·赫伯特原著小说《沙丘》改编
丹尼斯·维伦纽瓦作品
【 沙 丘 第 二 部 】